Chicago, Ill. Waveland Avenue Congregational Church records, 1876-1980. RG5222
Congregational Library & Archives
Chicago, Ill. Waveland Avenue Congregational Church records, 1876-1980.
Congregational Library & Archives
Waveland Avenue Congregational Church (Chicago, Ill.)
RG5222
1.09 Cubic Feet (1 box)
The church was first gathered in 1876 under the leadership of Andrew Brotherstone. In 1894, the Waveland Avenue Congregationalist Church officially joined the associated Chicago area Congregationalist churches. In 1961, the church joined the United Church of Christ. The church served its community until 1982 when it permanently closed. The collection includes board reports, financial records, and administrative records.
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
Gift from the Chicago Theological Seminary in 2014; Accession: 2014-69.
Historical Note
The church was first gathered in 1876 under the leadership of Andrew Brotherstone. In 1894, the Waveland Avenue Congregationalist Church officially joined the associated Chicago area Congregationalist churches. In 1961, the church joined the United Church of Christ. The church served its community until 1982 when it permanently closed.
Scope and Contents
The Waveland Avenue Congregational Church records include board reports, meeting minutes of the prudential committee, financial records, church meeting minutes and administrative records, church calendars and scheduling information, and the church's constitution.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged chronologically.
Bibliography
Taylor, Richard H. Congregational and Plan of Union Churches in the Great Lakes States. Vol. 5. Providence: Richard H. Taylor Publishing, 2009. [9.3.246]
Church records and registers.; Church finance.; Church history.; Christian education of children.; Chicago (Ill.) -- Church history.; Waveland Avenue Congregational Church (Chicago, Ill.)
- Meeting minutes with Constitution, 1876-1897 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Board of trustees record book, 1898-1905 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Church calendar, 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Newsletters, 1909-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Finances, 1910-1922 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Prudential committee minutes, 1916-1923 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Meeting minutes, 1924-1945 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Prudential committee minutes, 1924-1930 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Clerk Reports, 1924-1929 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Alphabetized Correspondences, 1925-1931 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Annual Reports, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Memorial Gifts and donations, 1952-1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- History of Waveland Sunday School, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Schedule and Calendar Book, 1956-1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Board of Trustee's Minutes, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Church Council meeting minutes, 1959-1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Confirmations, 1964-1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Church Council meeting minutes, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Annual Reports, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- United Church of Christ reports, 1968-1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Annual Reports, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Annual Reports, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Centennial Celebration and Preparation, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Annual Reports, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- History and Reminiscences, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Fabric from Goodrich Girls' School in China, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)